# DAVID JOHN

91-9699357407 david828john@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/in/thedavidjohn

## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A passionate, hands-on professional, I have around 9.5 years of experience in Java and Scala development. I have an extensive software engineering experience building products and web applications in Payments, Retail and Manufacturing domains. I keep atop of new developments within the industry and can adapt quickly to new coding conventions.

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Java, Scala.
- **Backend:** Spring Boot, Microservices, Spring Security, Spring MVC, Hibernate, SOAP and RESTful Webservices, Play Framework, Slick, Akka.
- Frontend: Angular 12, JavaScript, JSP.
- Databases: Oracle 11g/12c, SQL, MongoDB.
- Testing: Junit, SOAPUI.
- Tools: Eclipse IDE, Jenkins, Maven, SVN, JIRA, GIT, SQL Developer, Notepad++, Putty, Agile Central.
- Methodologies: OOP, Data structures and Algorithms, Design Patterns, Agile, Waterfall model.
- Application servers: Apache Tomcat, Oracle Weblogic, IBM Websphere.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **Senior Software Engineer**

#### Mastercard

January 2020 - Present

Location: Pune, India.

- Designed and developed "Batch UI" functionality in Scala, Play and Slick framework which allows branch users to upload transaction files and convert them into acceptable format seamlessly.
- Introduced Akka Actor using Scala in a legacy project to asynchronously process transaction files.
- Created a Sync Utility to be used by Biz Ops team to sync Cardholder data from one project to another, saving hours of manual work.

## **Senior Software Engineer**

## **Zensar Technologies**

September 2018- December 2019

Inhouse Collections Product for John Lewis Partnership.

Location: Pune, India.

- Designed and developed the end-to-end "Assign Accounts to Collector" module using Spring Boot, Spring Security, Hibernate and JSP which allows debt accounts to be assigned to collector agents.
- Created a Jenkins devops pipeline from scratch for Continuous Deployment of John Lewis's CMS application called ProductHub.
- Built the complete "Difficult Accounts" module for assigning defaulter debt accounts to legal authorities.
- Using Java 8's Stream API, decreased the number of database calls significantly during page load, and thus lowered the page loading time by 80%.

Module Lead Mindtree Limited June 2017- August 2018

Global PayPlus (GPP) for Fundtech India Pvt Ltd.

Location: Pune, India.

- Implemented end-to-end "Cancellation of Payment" flow for NPP, an Australian payments platform.
- Built the complete advising functionality for bank-to-clearing communications in GPP High value generic flow.
- Implemented core functionality of "Membership Upload" profile for a payments clearing house in Greece.
- Developed automation test cases in SoapUI using Groovy scripts to assist the testers to test for different payment scenarios in much quicker time (Before: 20 minutes per scenario, After: 1 minute per scenario).
- Resolved various defects (GUI related and payment processing related) for end-to-end payment process in GPP engine.

Steam Turbine Integrated Tools Suite

Location: Pune, India

- Module lead for one of the modules (D000 detailed design).
- Built two key plugins (Wrapper calculators and F2JTranslation) using Java 8 for improving accuracy of calculations of turbine parameters.
- Implemented logging mechanism for a calculation step from scratch in D000 detailed design.
- Contributed in developing and redesigning new versions of existing plugins.
- Monitored build failures on Jenkins and resolving them, made sure that code written by module members is reusable, maintainable and non-repetitive.

# Toolbox V2 application for Boeing

- Created a module "Parts" using Java, Spring MVC and Hibernate to help the user to modify or add information of airplane parts for his/her airlines.
- Also worked on the testing lifecycle of various user stories, did unit testing and integration testing on the developer environment.

# Maintenance performance toolbox application for Boeing

- Deployed latest build received from development team on to Boeing's cloud servers.
- Processing of client raw data (SGML) to application readable XML data on Boeing's Factory application.
- Communicated technical issues to non-technical management, wrote delivery estimates for new assignments.
- Engaged in various testing processes like smoke testing, functional testing and regression testing.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Mumbai, Maharashtra

# **University of Mumbai**

March 2005 - June 2011

- Bachelor's in Engineering, Vidyalankar's Institute of Technology. (Aggregate: 60.45 %)
- Class XII, S.I.E.S College of arts, science and commerce. (Aggregate: 84.50 %)
- Class X, S.I.E.S high school. (Aggregate: 82.80 %)

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

- Hobbies: Cricket, Movies, Music, Tennis, Astronomy and Stoicism.
- Spoken Languages: English, Hindi, Tamil and Marathi.
- Date of birth: 01- May- 1990.